A Guide to the Records of the American Association of University Women, Arlington Branch, 1943-2005
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Records of the American Association of University Women, Arlington Branch, 1943-2005
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 33
18 boxes.
American Association of University Women. Arlington Branch
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Arlington Branch of the American Association of University Women in 1996, 2004, and 2005.
Historical Information
The American Association of University Women (AAUW) unites the graduates of regionally accredited institutions of higher education in order to promote education and equity for all women and girls. It is composed of three corporations: the Association with more than 1600 branches which lobby for education and equity, the AAUW Educational Foundation which funds research on girls and education and grants fellowships for women, and the AAUW Legal Advocacy Fund which provides funds for women seeking judicial redress for sex discrimination in higher education.
The AAUW's Arlington Branch was founded in November 1943 with 20 charter members, and received official recognition in 1944. Currently, general membership meetings are held nine times a year, and there are seven interest or study groups. The Branch, currently with over 200 members, contributes to the Educational Foundation and Legal Advocacy Fund, promotes study and action in community and cultural interests, education and international relations, and cooperates in the Association's Virginia State and South Atlantic regional work. Through the years, study groups included as their focus: international affairs, art, literature, music, antiques, social policy, education and legislation.
The Arlington Branch received the Five Star Award each year, 1994-2001, and the new Twenty-first Century Recognition Award in 2002. These awards honor branches that apply and demonstrate meeting at least five of seven criteria including: (1) a net 5% growth in membership; (2)-(3)high donations to the Educational Foundation and Legal Advocacy Fund; (4) community action projects relating to education and equity for women and girls; (5)sustained public advocacy; (6) proven local visibility through public action; and (7) branch member attendance at AAUW state, regional, and national meetings.
Scope and Content
Record Group 33 houses the official records of the Arlington, Virginia Branch of the American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1943-2005. The record group measures approximately 11.5 linear feet. This record group documents the changing emphasis of the AAUW's Arlington Branch over more than 50 years on issues such as the environment, integration in education and employment, and especially equity for girls and women in all levels of education and in other aspects of life such as employment. Records concern not only the Arlington Branch's activities, but its relationship with the national organization, and contains some general AAUW materials. Most notable of these relate to the AAUW National Conference.
Types of material documenting the Branch's activities include: executive board and general meeting minutes, bylaws, financial records, correspondence, yearbooks and bulletins, reports to the regional and national AAUW, photographs, scrapbooks, clippings and other memorabilia. There are three binders containing scrapbooks, and a Cards Box holding cards containing information on individual members. There is also documentation on special projects for the Arlington Branch, which include several youth education initiatives and the branch's 25th and 50th anniversary celebrations.
Arrangement
Record Group 33 is arranged into ten series by type of material. Series 6, Publications, has three subseries: branch yearbooks, branch bulletins, and other publications. Within series the arrangement is chiefly chronological. An exception is Series 10, Special Projects, which is chiefly alphabetical in separate alphabets reflecting donations made in different years. Accretions over time have been folded into the original structure of the files.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Researchers interested in Arlington-wide women's organizations may also wish to see RG 16, Arlington Federation of Women's Clubs, RG 17, Organized Women Voters of Arlington County, RG 44, Arlington League of Women Voters, RG 131, Zonta Club of Arlington County, RG 156, Records of Soroptimists International of Arlington County, RG 171, Arlington Women's Democratic Club, and RG 322, Records of the Arlington Women's Club.
Index Terms
Subjects:
American Assocation of University Women. Arlington Branch (Va.); Women in community organization; Women -- United States -- Societies and clubs.; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Bylaws, Policies, Resolutions
  - Arlington Branch Bylaws, 1946, 1948, 1961-62, 1970-71 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Bylaws, 1974, 1976, 1978-79, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Bylaws, 1982, 1985, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Bylaws, 1990, 1992, 1996-98 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Job Descriptions, 1960, 1978, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Policy Sheets, 1946-50, 1962, 1967, 1974, 1982, 1987, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Resolutions, 1965-67, 1973-79, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Resolutions, 1996 (Box 1)
  - AAUW Charter and Bylaws 1995 (Box 1)
  - AAUW Diversity Policy, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - Parliamentary Procedures, 1984-1998 (Box 1)
  - AAUW President's Tool Kit, 200 (Box 1)
  - AAUW Change Management Tool Kit, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Nominations and Elections (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Parliamentarian's Policies (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Policy Sheets, 1995, 1997-2000 (Box 1)
- Membership
  - 1945-1958 (Box 1)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1959-1961 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1961-1983 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1984-1985, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1986-1987, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1988-1989, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1990-1991, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Lists, 1992-1993, 1993-1994, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Cards, 1968-1969, 1992 (1) (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Membership Cards, 1968-1969, 1992 (2) (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Member List and Dues Paid, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Member List and Dues Paid, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Dues Paid, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Former Member Cards, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Non-current Member Cards (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Member Cards, C-Z, 1998-1999 (1) (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Member Cards, C-Z, 1998-1999 (2) (Box 2)
  - Honorary Life Member Applications, 1999 (Box 2)
  - College & University Institutional Members, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Membership Survey, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Membership Brochures (Box 2)
  - Membership and Officer Forms (Box 2)
- Agendas and Minutes
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, January 1944-June 1947 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, December 1943-June 1948 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1947-May 1949 (Box 2)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1948-May 1955 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1949-June 1954 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1954-June 1956 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1955-May 1958 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1956-June 1960 (1) (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1956-June 1960 (2) (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1958-May 1960 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1960-May 1962 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1960-May 1962 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1962-August 1963 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1962-May 1963 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1963-June 1964 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1963-May 1964 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1964-June 1965 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1964-May 1965 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1965-June 1966 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1965-May 1966 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1966-May 1967 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1966-May 1967 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1967-May 1968 (Box 3)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1967-May 1971 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1968-May 1973 (1) (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1968-May 1973 (2) (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1968-May 1973 (3) (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1971-May 1973 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1973-July 1975 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1973-May 1975 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1975-July 1976 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1975-May 1977 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1976-June 1978 (1) (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1976-June 1978 (2) (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1977-May 1978 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1978-June 1979 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1978-May 1979 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1979-June 1980 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1979-May 1980 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1980-June 1981 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1980-May 1981 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1981-June 1982 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1981-May 1982 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, July 1982-July 1983 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1982-May 1983 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, September 1983-May 1984 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1983-May 1984 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1984-May 1985 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1984-May 1985 (Box 4)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1985-June 1986 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1985-April 1986 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1986-May 1987 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1986-May 1987 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1987-June 1989 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1987-April 1989 (1) (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1987-April 1989 (2) (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1989-June 1992 (1) (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1989-June 1992 (2) (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1991 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, August 1992-March 1994 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, February 1992-November 1993 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, April 1994-May 1996 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, May 1994-March 1996 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, July 1996-May 1997 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, September 1996-May 1997 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Minutes; Computer disk, 1999-2001 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Agendas & Minutes, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Meetings, Agendas & Minutes, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Board Minutes, Strategic Plan, 2002 (Box 5)
- Financial Records
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, June 1955-June 1958 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, October 1958-May 1962 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, September 1962-November 1964 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, April 1965-December 1969 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, January 1970-April 1975 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, June 1977-June 1980 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, July 1980-June 1982 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, July 1982-June 1983 (Box 5)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, July 1983-June 1984 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, July 1984-June 1986 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, August 1986-August 1987 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, September 1987-August 1988 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, September 1988-August 1989 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, September 1989-May 1991 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Treasurer's Reports, June 1991-July 1995 (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch receipts, October 1987-June 1993 (1) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch receipts, October 1987-June 1993 (2) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch receipts, October 1987-June 1993 (3) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch receipts, October 1987-June 1993 (4) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch receipts, October 1987-June 1993 (5) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Deposit Records, 1985-1992 (1) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Deposit Records, 1985-1992 (2) (Box 6)
  - Arlington Branch Bank Statements & Canceled Checks, 1987-1993 (1) (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch Bank Statements & Canceled Checks, 1987-1993 (2) (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch Bank Statements & Canceled Checks, 1987-1993 (3) (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch EFP Deposit Records, 1985-1990 (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch EFP Bank Statements & Canceled Checks, 1987-1993 (1) (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch EFP Bank Statements & Canceled Checks, 1987-1993 (2) (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch EFP Reports, 1994-1996 (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch Check Stubs; First Virginia, 1985-1992 (Box 7)
  - Arlington Branch Deposit Slips: First Virginia, 1993-1995 (Box 8)
  - Arlington Branch Statements and Checks: General: First Virginia, 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Arlington Branch Statements: Savings Account: First Virginia, 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - Arlington Branch Statments: Columbia First/First Union, 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Arlington Branch Statements and Checks: General: First Virginia, 1997-1999 (Box 8)
  - Arlington Branch Statements: CD: First Virginia, 1997-1999 (Box 8)
  - Arlington Branch Statements: EFP: First Virginia, 1997-1999 (Box 8)
  - Paid Bills, 1993-1995 (Box 8)
- Arlington Branch Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1945-1965 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1989 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (Sufit), March 1990-April 1992 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (Huntington), June 1992-May 1994 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, July 1994-December 1994 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, January 1995-December 1995 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, October 1995-December 1995 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, January 1996-May 1996 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, n.d., June 1996-September 2001 (Box 9)
  - AAUW Stationary (Box 9)
- Publications
  - Yearbooks
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks, 1946-1957 (Box 9)
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks, 1958-1970 (Box 9)
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks, 1971-1982 (Box 9)
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks, 1991-1996 (Box 9)
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks & Networking Directory, 1983-1990 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks, 1996/97-1997-98 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Yearbooks, 1998/99-1999/2000 (Box 10)
  - Bulletins
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1955-May 1956 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, June 1961-June 1964 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1964-June 1966 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1966-June 1968 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1968-June 1970 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1970-November 1972 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, December 1972-June 1975 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1975-June 1977 (Box 10)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1977-June 1978 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1978-June 1979 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1979-June 1980 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1980-June 1981 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1981-June 1982 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1982-June 1983 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1983-June 1984 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1984-June 1986 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1986-May 1987 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1987-May 1989 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, June 1989-June 1990 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1993-June 1995 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1995-June 1996 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1996-June 1997 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1997-June 1998 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1998-June 1999 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 1999-June 2000 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 2000-June 2001 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 2001-June 2002 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 2002-June 2003 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, September 2003-June 2004 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Branch Bulletins, November 2004-April 2005 (Box 12)
  - Other Publications
    - AAUW Virginia Division Bulletins, 1955-1956, 1965, 1968 (Box 12)
    - International Federation of University Women Newsletter, 1955 (Box 12)
    - "The Arlington Difference," 1983 (Box 12)
    - "Notable Women of Arlington," 1993 (Box 12)
    - "Names Honored" (AAUW Educational Foundation), 1983-1989 (Box 12)
    - "Names Honored" (AAUW Educational Foundation), 1990-1994 (Box 12)
    - AAUW Directory of Fellows & Grant Recipients, 1988-1991 (Box 12)
    - AAUW Directory of Fellowship & Grant Recipients, 1991-1995 (Box 12)
    - AAUW "Missing Fellows" List, 1988 (Box 13)
    - "Congress and You," 1969 (Box 13)
    - "Educating Americans for the 21st Century" (Box 13)
    - "How to Involve Limited English Proficient Parents and Students," 1985-1986 (Box 13)
    - AAUW Legislative History and Policy Notes, 1975-1977 (Box 13)
    - "Northern Virginia Sun: Fifty-Two Weeks of One Man's Opinion," 1985-1986 (Box 13)
    - "Selecting School Board Candidates in Arlington County, Virginia," 1949 (Box 13)
    - Shaping the Future of Women and Girls: AAUW Educational Foundation Report," 1990-1992 (Box 13)
    - "Virginia Women's Cultural History Project," 1983 (Box 13)
    - "Washington Opportunities for Women," 1967 (Box 13)
    - VOLT: Leadership Training Manual Draft, 1986 (Box 13)
    - VOLT: Training Manual Notes, 1986 (Box 13)
    - VOLT: Leadership Training Manual Handouts, 1987 (Box 13)
    - VOLT: Leadership Training Manual, Level I, 1987 (Box 13)
    - VOLT: Leadership Training Manual, 1988 (Box 14)
    - VOLT: Leadership Training Manual Handouts, 1988 (Box 14)
    - History of the Arlington Branch, 1943-1997 (Box 14)
    - Regional and Divisional AAUW History, 1975-1976 (Box 14)
    - Histories of AAUW Branches, 1945-1984 (Box 14)
    - National AAUW History, 1956-1988 (Box 14)
- Regional State & National Reports & Convention Materials
  - Arlington Branch Regional & National Reports, 1944-1950 (Box 14)
  - Arlington Branch Regional & National Reports, 1951-1960 (Box 14)
  - Arlington Branch Regional & National Reports, 1961-1969 (Box 14)
  - Arlington Branch Regional & National Reports, 1971-1975 (Box 14)
  - Virginia State Division Branch Presidents, 1972-1973 (Box 15)
  - Northern Virginia AAUW Conference on Girls in Education Materials, October 1994 (Box 15)
  - Virginia AAUW Convention Materials, April 1995 (Box 15)
  - Virginia AAUW Convention Materials, April 1996 (Box 15)
  - National AAUW Centennial Celebration, 1988 (Box 15)
  - AAUW South Atlantic Regional Conference Materials, June 1996 (Box 15)
  - AAUW National Convention Materials, June 1995 (Box 15)
- Memorabilia
  - Arlington AAUW Photographs, 1983-1990 (1) (Box 15)
  - Arlington AAUW Photographs, 1983-1990 (2) (Box 15)
  - Arlington AAUW Photographs, 1983-1990 (3) (Box 15)
  - Arlington AAUW Clippings (Box 15)
  - Certificates of Commendation & Appreciation for Arlington AAUW (unframed), 1976-1996 (Box 15)
  - Three Certificates of Commendation (framed), 1988-1991 (1) (Box 15)
  - Three Certificates of Commendation (framed), 1988-1991 (2) (Box 15)
  - Three Certificates of Commendation (framed), 1988-1991 (3) (Box 15)
  - Arlington Bicentennial Certificate of Recognition, 1976 (Box 15)
  - Senior Citizens Day Center Certificate (Box 15)
  - Photographs, 1952, 1962-1976 (Box 15)
  - Photographs, 1980s-2000 (Box 15)
  - Photographs, 2000-2001 (Box 15)
  - Clippings, 1953-1991 (Box 15)
- Scrapbooks (filed separately - see below)
- Special Projects
  - 25th Anniversary Celebration Materials, May 1969 (Box 15)
  - 50th Anniversary Celebration Materials, April 1994 (Box 15)
  - Bicentennial Information, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Educational Excellence Materials, 1981-1985 (Box 16)
  - Educational Foundation, 1988-1994 (Box 16)
  - Educational Foundation Research Project Grants, 1990-1992 (Box 16)
  - National Women's Hall of Fame Application for Elizabeth Campbell, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Partnerships in Education Materials, 1984-1994 (Box 16)
  - Sister City Information, 1991-1995 (1) (Box 16)
  - Sister City Information, 1991-1995 (2) (Box 16)
  - American Family Project, 1964 (Box 16)
  - Arlington County Commission on the Status of Women, 1991-2001 (Box 16)
  - Awards Luncheon, 1996-2002 (Box 16)
  - Candidates Forum, 1998-2001 (Box 16)
  - College Faculty Program, 1962-1967 (Box 16)
  - Educational Equity Initiative, 1991-1994 (Box 16)
  - Educational Foundation: General, 1995-2002 (Box 16)
  - Educational Foundation Contribution Reports, 1986-1996 (Box 16)
  - Educational Foundation Fundraising Events Invitations, 1987-1993 (Box 16)
  - Educational Foundation Named Gifts, 1980-2000 (Box 16)
  - Educator of the Year, 1997-2003 (Box 17)
  - Five Star Award Applications, 1994-1996 (Box 17)
  - Five Star Award Applications, 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Five Star Award Applications, 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Five Star Award Applications, 2001 (Box 17)
  - 21st Century Recognition Program Applications, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
  - Insurance, 1995-1996 (Box 17)
  - Interbranch Council, 1976-1979 (Box 17)
  - International Coffees Archives, 1962-1999 (Box 17)
  - Legal Advocacy Fund, 1997-2001 (Box 17)
  - Legislative Activities, 1947-1969 (Box 17)
  - Legislative Activities, 1970-1977 (Box 17)
  - Northern Virginia Community College Educational Foundation, 1992 (Box 17)
  - Pay Equity, 1995-1999 (Box 17)
  - Progress in Equity Nominations, 1996-2000 (Box 18)